DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: dbr:Die_schöne_Müllerin
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Manifestation

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | 《美丽的磨坊女》（德语：Die schöne Müllerin，作品号25，D. 795）是由弗朗茨·舒伯特基于德国诗人威廉·米勒诗作改编的声乐套曲，创作于1823年。在此之后，舒伯特还为米勒的《冬之旅》配了曲。它是最早的一部被广为传唱的声乐套曲之一，也是舒伯特最为重要的作品之一，被视为艺术歌曲这一体裁的一部巅峰之作。 这部套曲原先是为男高音及女高音而作，后来被改为其他音域。由于歌词所讲是一位男青年的故事，因而这部作品经常由男歌唱家演绎。这部作品的钢琴部分不仅仅只是人声的伴奏，并且承担了这部作品相当大的比重。 这部作品演奏时长通常在60至70分钟之间。
dbo:abstract | 歌曲集『美しき水車小屋の娘』（うつくしきすいしゃごやのむすめ、Die schöne Müllerin）作品25、D795はフランツ・シューベルトが作曲した全20曲からなる歌曲集。一般に「冬の旅」・「白鳥の歌」と並び「シューベルト3大歌曲集」の一つと称される。一部では「美しき水車屋の娘」と呼ばれることもある。
dbo:abstract | Die Schöne Müllerin (em português, "A Bela Moleira"), Op.25, D 795, é um ciclo de canções compostas por Franz Schubert, para piano e solo vocal, baseadas em poemas de Wilhelm Müller.
dbo:abstract | Die schöne Müllerin (Op. 25, D. 795), is a song cycle by Franz Schubert based on poems by Wilhelm Müller. It is the earliest extended song cycle to be widely performed. The work is considered one of Schubert's most important cycles, and one of the pinnacles of Lied, and it is widely performed and recorded. Die schöne Müllerin is performed by a pianist and a solo singer. The vocal part falls in the range of a tenor or soprano voice, but is often sung by other voices, transposed to a lower range. Since the story of the cycle is about a young man, the work is most often sung by men. The piano part bears much of the expressive burden of the work, and is only seldom a mere "accompaniment" to the singer. A typical performance lasts around sixty to seventy minutes.
dbo:abstract | Piękna Młynarka (niem. Die schöne Müllerin), op. 25, D 795 – cykl pieśni skomponowany w 1823 roku przez Franza Schuberta do poezji Wilhelma Müllera. Pierwsze wydanie ukazało się w 1824 r. Cykl przeznaczony jest na głos z towarzyszeniem fortepianu. Ponieważ tekst opowiada o młodym człowieku, utwór wykonywany jest najczęściej przez mężczyzn. Standardowe wykonanie trwa około godziny.
dbo:abstract | Die schöne Müllerin D 795 Op. 25 (La bella mugnaia) è un ciclo di 20 lieder composti da Franz Schubert nel 1823 sui testi di Wilhelm Müller, poeta romantico minore, che aveva composto un omonimo ciclo di poesie. Di soli tre anni più vecchio di Schubert, morirà anch'egli in giovane età. Il ciclo narra la storia di un giovane mugnaio che lascia la propria casa e, incamminandosi lungo la via indicata dal ruscello, arriva in un altro mulino. La bellezza del posto e l'amore che prova per una giovane e bella mugnaia lo trattiene in quel luogo. Il ragazzo mette in atto una serie di azioni spinto dai sentimenti che pervadono il suo animo e dal desiderio che questi vengano ricambiati dalla bella mugnaia. Quando finalmente questo avviene, spunta inaspettatamente un terzo incomodo, un cacciatore, che conquisterà facilmente il cuore della sua amata. La tristezza per il perduto amore non permetterà al giovane di sopravvivere e il desiderio di morte sarà cantato dallo stesso ruscello. Il protagonista assoluto dei lieder è il giovane mugnaio; quanto narrato è visto attraverso le sue parole e i suoi sentimenti. Tuttavia l'elemento essenziale della poetica è l'acqua che scorre, parla, canta. Le poesie sono piene di sfumature e molto delicate. Schubert ne ha colto completamente lo spirito. La parte musicale integra ed arricchisce la parte poetica. Di seguito si riporta un breve escursus del ciclo. 1. * Il viaggiare (Das Wandern) Il primo lied riprende il tema del viandante, caro al periodo romantico. Esprime il piacere di mettersi in cammino verso nuove mete. Il piano evoca l'instancabile e continuo movimento della ruota del mulino, a simboleggiare il peregrinare dell'uomo. 2. * Dove? (Wohin?) Mentre il pianoforte evoca il mormorio del ruscello il mugnaio lo interroga per sapere dove lo condurrà. 3. * Arrivo (Halt!) Il mugnaio nel suo peregrinare lungo il corso del ruscello scopre una bella casetta accanto ad un mulino e decide di fermarsi. Il canto esprime la felicità del giovane per il luogo che il ruscello gli ha fatto scoprire. 4. * Ringraziamento al ruscello (Danksagung an den Bach) Il mugnaio che cercava lavoro scorge nella casetta una bella mugnaia. Il suo cuore è felice e il suo innamoramento repentino. Il canto esprime questo stato d'animo. 5. * Sera di festa (Am Feierabend) Il giovane si chiede se le sue forze sono sufficienti per quel mulino e per conquistare il cuore della ragazza. Quest'ultima dopo essersi intrattenuta con i lavoranti dà a tutti la buona notte e si ritira. 6. * Il curioso (Der Neugierige) I fiori e le stelle sono interrogati dal ragazzo che vuole conoscere se la bella mugnaia lo ama. Poi si rivolge al ruscello con tutta la soavità di cui è capace, espresso dalla melodia "O Bächlein meine Liebe" (O ruscello, amore mio) "Sag,Bächlein, liebt sie micht" (Dimmi, riuscello, lei mi ama?). 7. * Impazienza (Ungeduld) Un canto impetuoso e un accompagnamento velocissimo esprimono l'impazienza che il giovane mostra nel voler conquistare il cuore della mugnaia. Vuole il suo cuore e lo vuole per sempre. Viene qui espresso l'ideale di ogni giovane nell'amore imperituro. 8. * Saluto del mattino (Morgengruß) Con le parole "Guten Morgen, schöne Müllerin" ha inizio questo lied pervaso da un'armonia che richiama la freschezza del mattino. La fanciulla viene invitata a farsi vedere e poi richiamata per essere solo apparsa fugacemente. 9. * I fiori del mugnaio (Des Müllers Blumen) Il giovane raccoglie, sulla sponda del ruscello, dei fiori azzurri come gli occhi della sua bella. Li depone poi sulla finestra affinché non si dimentichi di lui. 10. * Pioggia di lacrime (Tränenregen) Finalmente i due ragazzi sono soli sulla sponda del ruscello. Non si comprende se la scena rappresenti la realtà o sia la fantasia a far vedere quello che sente il cuore del giovane. La scena muta. L'acqua del ruscello si increspa, le immagini dei due ragazzi si dissolvono. Il tempo cambia, la pioggia incombe, la ragazza rientra in casa e quella pioggia si trasforma in lacrime. 11. * Mia! (Mein!) Finalmente la mugnaia accetta le attenzioni del giovane che esulta esclamando "Mia". Il canto esprime la felicità e la contenuta eccitazione per l'avvenuto incontro. Il ragazzo chiede al ruscello di fermare le sue acque e di non mormorare più; analogamente vuole che anche gli uccelli smettano di cantare. Tutto deve fermarsi per fissare questo felice istante. 12. * Pausa (Pause) La felicità del ragazzo gli impedisce di fare qualunque cosa. Appende il liuto alla parete ornandolo con un nastro verde (il colore preferito dalla mugnaia). Solo il vento si posa sulle corde dello strumento ricavandone un flebile suono. 13. * Il liuto con il nastro verde (Mit dem grünen Lautenbande) Il nastro verde (il colore della speranza) del liuto sbiadisce. 14. * Il cacciatore (Der Jäger) Inaspettato arriva un cacciatore. Cosa vuole? Non c'è cacciagione per lui in questo luogo. Vada via. Il mugnaio è agitato, teme il rivale. Questa particolare situazione è resa prima con il pianoforte che evoca i suoni della caccia. Il canto è invece fortemente sillabato e nello stesso tempo molto veloce ad indicare lo stato d'animo del giovane timoroso di perdere la sua amata. 15. * Gelosia e fierezza (Eifersucht und Stolz) "Keh um" ("Voltati", "Vattene"). Con questo grido il mugnaio vorrebbe allontanare il cacciatore che confida al ruscello le sue pene e la paura che il cacciatore gli porti via la sua amata. Però è anche orgoglioso e non vuole che questi suoi timori vengano rivelati alla mugnaia. Chiede così al ruscello di dirle solo che sta intagliando uno zufolo per suonare. 16. * L'amato colore (Die liebe Farbe) I timori del giovane si sono purtroppo avverati. La ragazza gli ha preferito il cacciatore. Viene ripreso il tema del colore verde di cui il giovane parla con grande mestizia. Continuerà ad essere il colore da lui amato perché anche lei lo amava. Anch'egli diventerà cacciatore perché a lei piace. La sua preda sarà tuttavia la morte e nella sua tomba sarà presente il verde. Il canto è pieno di malinconia ed il pianoforte lo sostiene in modo mirabile. Alla conclusione il canto si trasforma in pianto mentre il pianoforte insiste sulla stessa nota. Questo espediente, che ben esprime angoscia e tristezza, sarà ripreso la Fryderyk Chopin nel Preludio della goccia. 17. * Il cattivo colore (Die böse Farbe) Il colore che finora era amato viene ora duramente detestato. Nell'odio per il colore si cela la disperazione per l'amore perduto e per il voltafaccia dell'amata. Il canto è piuttosto duro ed è un grido di addio. Torna il ritmo della caccia e il disprezzo del mugnaio per il cacciatore. 18. * Fiori appassiti ("Trockne Blumen) Una stupenda melodia e un canto accorato. Il mugnaio chiede che i fiori ormai appassiti dotatigli dalla mugnaia vengano deposti sulla sua tomba. Quindi immagina che l'amata passi vicino alla sua tomba e pensi che lui le era rimasto fedele. Il canto finisce con un estremo momento di speranza dove le strofe dicono maggio sta arrivando, l'inverno se ne va. Il tema verrà elaborato dall'autore nelle Variazioni sul tema 'Trockne Blumen' per pianoforte e flauto D 802 (opera postuma 160). 19. * Il mugnaio e il ruscello (Der Müller und der Bach) In questo canto all'interprete vengono fatte cantare parole ora del ruscello ora del mugnaio. Il mugnaio sta morendo e chiede al ruscello di cantargli una ninna nanna. Il ruscello lo rassicura dicendo che in cielo i suoi desideri saranno esauditi a cui risponde con estrema dolcezza e riconoscenza il mugnaio. 20. * Ninna nanna del ruscello (Das Baches Wiegenlied) Una ninna nanna dolcissima chiude il ciclo. Il ruscello augura al mugnaio la buona notte che deve portare con sé la morte ma anche la fine delle pene del ragazzo.
dbo:abstract | «Прекрасная мельничиха» (op.25, D795) (нем. Die schöne Müllerin) — первый вокальный цикл Франца Шуберта на слова Вильгельма Мюллера. Состоит из 20 песен. Сочинён в 1823 году, за четыре года до второго цикла «Зимний путь». На русском языке известен в переводе И. Тюменева и А. Машистова. В песнях рассказывается о юном мельнике, который отправляется в странствия искать счастье. Он видит мельницу и влюбляется в дочь местного мельника. Любовь приносит ему радостные, а затем и горестные переживания: у него появляется более счастливый соперник, охотник. Вновь отправившись в странствия, юноша рассказывает ручью как единственному верному другу о своей потерянной любви и после этого хочет оставить свою любовь на дне ручья
dbo:abstract | Die schöne Müllerin (op. 25, D. 795) ist ein Liederzyklus für Singstimme und Klavier von Franz Schubert, der 1823 komponiert wurde. Textbasis des Zyklus ist die Gedichtsammlung Die schöne Müllerin von Wilhelm Müller, die in den 1821 erschienenen Sieben und siebzig nachgelassenen Gedichten aus den Papieren eines reisenden Waldhornisten enthalten ist. Schubert hat von den 25 Gedichten 20 vertont, wodurch die vom Dichter intendierte Ironie im romantischen Sinne und der pessimistische Schluss aufgehoben wurden. Der Inhalt bezieht sich – biographischen Quellen und Briefen zufolge – auf Müllers unerfüllte Liebe zu Luise Hensel.
dbo:abstract | Die schöne Müllerin (La bella molinera), D. 795, es un ciclo de lieder compuesto por Franz Schubert sobre poemas de Wilhelm Müller. Es el primer ciclo de canciones que se popularizó. Es una de las obras maestras de Schubert, y se interpreta y graba con frecuencia. Es uno de los primeros ciclos de lieder completos de la época romántica, donde el compositor, siguiendo el hilo de una historia completa, utiliza diferentes registros musicales para explicar plenamente las peripecias sucesivas. La bella molinera ilustra, con Viaje de invierno, el apogeo de la música de cámara en el siglo XIX.
dbo:abstract | Die schöne Müllerin (de mooie molenaarster) is een liederencyclus (opus 25, D 795, 1823) van Franz Schubert.De cyclus bestaat uit 20 getoonzette gedichten van Wilhelm Müller. Met elkaar vormen de gedichten het verhaal van een rondtrekkende gezel, die op een molen komt te werken en daar verliefd wordt op de dochter van de molenaar. Deze valt echter voor de charmes van een jager. De gezel verdrinkt daarna in de molenbeek. Vooral het eerste lied is populair en wordt dikwijls (met name in Duitstalige landen) tijdens het wandelen gezongen. Das Wandern ist des Müllers Lust,Das Wandern!Das muß ein schlechter Müller sein,Dem niemals fiel das Wandern ein,Das Wandern.
dbo:abstract | La Belle Meunière Pour l’article homonyme, voir La Belle Meunière (film). Die schöne Müllerin (en français La Belle Meunière), D. 795, est un cycle de Lieder écrit par le compositeur autrichien Franz Schubert. Composés probablement entre mai et décembre 1823, après une période de doute et de tentatives avortées (symphonies nos 7 et 8), Die Schöne Müllerin reprend 20 des 25 poèmes du même titre écrits par le poète allemand Wilhelm Müller (auteur aussi des textes du cycle suivant, Winterreise). Il s'agit là d'un des premiers cycles complets de Lieder de la période romantique, où le compositeur, suivant le fil conducteur d'une histoire complète, utilise différents registres musicaux pour exprimer pleinement les péripéties successives. Les thèmes développés sont typiquement romantiques : l'amour, l'espoir, la déception, la tristesse, la mort, la quête personnelle, le voyage, la nature. L'histoire est la suivante : un jeune homme, voyageant le long d'un ruisseau, arrive chez un meunier et tombe amoureux de sa fille. Mais la belle, d'abord bienveillante, préfère se laisser séduire par un chasseur. Le pauvre apprenti meunier s'en noie de chagrin et de désespoir. La cohérence du cycle est assurée par le thème du voyage : le ruisseau (fil conducteur et confident du narrateur), le promeneur, la nature. Mais les lieder sont tous particuliers, même si certains vont manifestement par paire. La première partie est joyeuse et pleine d'espoir, puis le ton s'obscurcit à partir de Der Jäger, pour devenir mélancolique, triste voire violent. Die schöne Müllerin a été interprété par de grands ténors et barytons comme Olaf Bär, Dietrich Fischer-Dieskau, Peter Pears, Peter Schreier, Fritz Wunderlich, Christoph Prégardien mais aussi par des altos comme Brigitte Fassbaender et Christa Ludwig et aussi par des contreténors comme Jochen Kowalski et a été enregistré de nombreuses fois. Die schöne Müllerin illustre avec Voyage d'hiver l'apogée de la musique des Lieder au XIXe siècle.
dbo:thumbnail | http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Franz_Schubert_c1827.jpg?width=300
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://librivox.org/sammlung-deutscher-gedichte-006-by-various/
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://members.macconnect.com/users/j/jimbob/classical/Schubert_D795.html#mueller
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.lieder.net/lieder/assemble_texts.html?SongCycleId=48
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.lieder.net/lieder/assemble_texts.html?LanguageId=7&SongCycleId=48
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://traffic.libsyn.com/gardnermuseum/schubert_op25.mp3
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.pianoaccompaniments.com/die-schone-mullerin.html
dbo:wikiPageID | 516061
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 717573681
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tenor
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Strophic_form
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/File:Franz_Schubert_c1827.jpg
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Otto_Erich_Deutsch
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Literature_in_English
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Journeyman
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Isabella_Stewart_Gardner_Museum
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Max_Friedlaender_(musicologist)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1823_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Comedy
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Anton_Diabelli
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_cycles_by_Franz_Schubert
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Wilhelm_Müller
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Franz_Schubert
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Classical_song_cycles_in_German
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/File:DasWandern.pdf
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Edition_Peters
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Jeremy_Denk
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:MP3
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Song_cycle
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Soprano
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Dietrich_Fischer-Dieskau
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fierrabras_(opera)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Lieder_composed_by_Franz_Schubert
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Fletcher_(playwright)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Adelaide_(Beethoven)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Franz_Liszt
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Musical_settings_of_poems_by_Wilhelm_Müller
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:William_Rowley
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Lied
dbp:cname | Die schöne Müllerin
dbp:work | Die Schöne Müllerin, D.795
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Classical_song_cycles_in_German
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_cycles_by_Franz_Schubert
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Musical_settings_of_poems_by_Wilhelm_Müller
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Lieder_composed_by_Franz_Schubert
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1823_compositions
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Cycle
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Cycle115287830
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/TimeInterval115269513
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Abstraction100002137
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Measure100033615
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatClassicalSongCycles
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatSongCycles
rdfs:comment | «Прекрасная мельничиха» (op.25, D795) (нем. Die schöne Müllerin) — первый вокальный цикл Франца Шуберта на слова Вильгельма Мюллера. Состоит из 20 песен. Сочинён в 1823 году, за четыре года до второго цикла «Зимний путь». На русском языке известен в переводе И. Тюменева и А. Машистова.
rdfs:comment | Die schöne Müllerin (op. 25, D. 795) ist ein Liederzyklus für Singstimme und Klavier von Franz Schubert, der 1823 komponiert wurde. Textbasis des Zyklus ist die Gedichtsammlung Die schöne Müllerin von Wilhelm Müller, die in den 1821 erschienenen Sieben und siebzig nachgelassenen Gedichten aus den Papieren eines reisenden Waldhornisten enthalten ist. Schubert hat von den 25 Gedichten 20 vertont, wodurch die vom Dichter intendierte Ironie im romantischen Sinne und der pessimistische Schluss aufgehoben wurden. Der Inhalt bezieht sich – biographischen Quellen und Briefen zufolge – auf Müllers unerfüllte Liebe zu Luise Hensel.
rdfs:comment | 歌曲集『美しき水車小屋の娘』（うつくしきすいしゃごやのむすめ、Die schöne Müllerin）作品25、D795はフランツ・シューベルトが作曲した全20曲からなる歌曲集。一般に「冬の旅」・「白鳥の歌」と並び「シューベルト3大歌曲集」の一つと称される。一部では「美しき水車屋の娘」と呼ばれることもある。
rdfs:comment | Die schöne Müllerin (de mooie molenaarster) is een liederencyclus (opus 25, D 795, 1823) van Franz Schubert.De cyclus bestaat uit 20 getoonzette gedichten van Wilhelm Müller. Met elkaar vormen de gedichten het verhaal van een rondtrekkende gezel, die op een molen komt te werken en daar verliefd wordt op de dochter van de molenaar. Deze valt echter voor de charmes van een jager. De gezel verdrinkt daarna in de molenbeek. Vooral het eerste lied is populair en wordt dikwijls (met name in Duitstalige landen) tijdens het wandelen gezongen.
rdfs:comment | Piękna Młynarka (niem. Die schöne Müllerin), op. 25, D 795 – cykl pieśni skomponowany w 1823 roku przez Franza Schuberta do poezji Wilhelma Müllera. Pierwsze wydanie ukazało się w 1824 r. Cykl przeznaczony jest na głos z towarzyszeniem fortepianu. Ponieważ tekst opowiada o młodym człowieku, utwór wykonywany jest najczęściej przez mężczyzn. Standardowe wykonanie trwa około godziny.
rdfs:comment | Die Schöne Müllerin (em português, "A Bela Moleira"), Op.25, D 795, é um ciclo de canções compostas por Franz Schubert, para piano e solo vocal, baseadas em poemas de Wilhelm Müller.
rdfs:comment | Die schöne Müllerin D 795 Op. 25 (La bella mugnaia) è un ciclo di 20 lieder composti da Franz Schubert nel 1823 sui testi di Wilhelm Müller, poeta romantico minore, che aveva composto un omonimo ciclo di poesie. Di soli tre anni più vecchio di Schubert, morirà anch'egli in giovane età. Di seguito si riporta un breve escursus del ciclo.
rdfs:comment | La Belle Meunière Pour l’article homonyme, voir La Belle Meunière (film). Die schöne Müllerin (en français La Belle Meunière), D. 795, est un cycle de Lieder écrit par le compositeur autrichien Franz Schubert. Composés probablement entre mai et décembre 1823, après une période de doute et de tentatives avortées (symphonies nos 7 et 8), Die Schöne Müllerin reprend 20 des 25 poèmes du même titre écrits par le poète allemand Wilhelm Müller (auteur aussi des textes du cycle suivant, Winterreise). Die schöne Müllerin illustre avec Voyage d'hiver l'apogée de la musique des Lieder au XIXe siècle.
rdfs:comment | 《美丽的磨坊女》（德语：Die schöne Müllerin，作品号25，D. 795）是由弗朗茨·舒伯特基于德国诗人威廉·米勒诗作改编的声乐套曲，创作于1823年。在此之后，舒伯特还为米勒的《冬之旅》配了曲。它是最早的一部被广为传唱的声乐套曲之一，也是舒伯特最为重要的作品之一，被视为艺术歌曲这一体裁的一部巅峰之作。 这部套曲原先是为男高音及女高音而作，后来被改为其他音域。由于歌词所讲是一位男青年的故事，因而这部作品经常由男歌唱家演绎。这部作品的钢琴部分不仅仅只是人声的伴奏，并且承担了这部作品相当大的比重。 这部作品演奏时长通常在60至70分钟之间。
rdfs:comment | Die schöne Müllerin (Op. 25, D. 795), is a song cycle by Franz Schubert based on poems by Wilhelm Müller. It is the earliest extended song cycle to be widely performed. The work is considered one of Schubert's most important cycles, and one of the pinnacles of Lied, and it is widely performed and recorded. A typical performance lasts around sixty to seventy minutes.
rdfs:comment | Die schöne Müllerin (La bella molinera), D. 795, es un ciclo de lieder compuesto por Franz Schubert sobre poemas de Wilhelm Müller. Es el primer ciclo de canciones que se popularizó. Es una de las obras maestras de Schubert, y se interpreta y graba con frecuencia. Es uno de los primeros ciclos de lieder completos de la época romántica, donde el compositor, siguiendo el hilo de una historia completa, utiliza diferentes registros musicales para explicar plenamente las peripecias sucesivas. La bella molinera ilustra, con Viaje de invierno, el apogeo de la música de cámara en el siglo XIX.
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
rdfs:label | La bella molinera
rdfs:label | Piękna młynarka
rdfs:label | 美しき水車小屋の娘
rdfs:label | 美丽的磨坊女
rdfs:label | Прекрасная мельничиха (Шуберт)
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
rdfs:label | Die schöne Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://nl.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://d-nb.info/gnd/300141629
owl:sameAs | http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.02kjy6
owl:sameAs | http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/美しき水車小屋の娘
owl:sameAs | http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/La_bella_molinera
owl:sameAs | http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Piękna_młynarka
owl:sameAs | http://d-nb.info/gnd/4464648-3
owl:sameAs | http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/아름다운_물방앗간의_처녀
owl:sameAs | dbr:Die_schöne_Müllerin
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_schöne_Müllerin
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Die_schöne_Müllerin?oldid=717573681
foaf:depiction | http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Franz_Schubert_c1827.jpg
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Die_schöne_Müllerin

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: http://dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Expression

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Work/runtime | 2.5166666666666666
dbo:aSide | "Rock and Roll Music"
dbo:abstract | I'm a Loser è un brano dei Beatles, contenuto nell'album Beatles for Sale del 1964. È stata scritta prevalentemente da John Lennon ed accreditata al duo Lennon/McCartney.
dbo:abstract | I'm a Loser Pistes de Beatles for Sale No Reply Baby's in Black I'm a Loser est une chanson des Beatles composée par John Lennon et créditée Lennon/McCartney. Il s'agit de la première chanson véritablement personnelle de Lennon, inspiré par Bob Dylan. Enregistrée en août 1964, elle paraît sur l'album Beatles for Sale (Beatles '65 aux États-Unis). Cette première incursion du groupe dans le registre folk a fait l'objet de quelques reprises. Il s'agit également de la dernière composition des Beatles dans laquelle apparaît un harmonica.
dbo:abstract | I’m a Loser is een nummer van The Beatles. Het staat op het album Beatles for Sale uit 1964. In het volgende jaar werd het opgenomen op het Amerikaanse album Beatles ’65. Het nummer is geschreven door John Lennon, maar staat, zoals gebruikelijk, op naam van Lennon-McCartney. Er is nog overwogen het nummer op single uit te brengen, maar de eerstvolgende Beatlessingle werd I Feel Fine. De muziekcriticus Richie Unterberger schreef in 2009 dat I'm a Loser een van de eerste Beatlesnummers is die over meer gaan dan alleen maar jeugdige liefde. Het lied gaat over afgewezen worden in de liefde, maar ook over de noodzaak om je groot te houden als je hele wereld in elkaar stort en het negatieve zelfbeeld dat je daaraan overhoudt.
dbo:abstract | "I'm a Loser" é uma canção composta por John Lennon e creditada a Lennon/McCartney. Foi gravada pela banda britânica The Beatles e lançada no álbum Beatles for Sale, de 1964.
dbo:abstract | I’m a Loser (engl. ‚Ich bin ein Verlierer‘) ist ein Lied der britischen Band The Beatles aus dem Jahr 1964. Komponiert wurde es von John Lennon, es steht jedoch unter dem bei der Band üblichen Copyright Lennon/McCartney.
dbo:abstract | "I'm a Loser" es una canción de The Beatles lanzada originalmente en el álbum Beatles for Sale. Estaba previsto que saliera como un sencillo en el Reino Unido hasta que John Lennon escribiera "I Feel Fine". En la primera edición de Beatles for Sale, la canción fue erróneamente impresa como "I'm a Losser". Esta canción ofreció la particularidad de que fue la última en que Lennon da un uso prominente a la armónica, instrumento que caracterizó varias de sus primeras composiciones con la banda (después la usó más esporádicamente en canciones como "All Together Now", "Being for the Benefit of Mr. Kite!" y "Rocky Racoon").
dbo:abstract | "I'm a Loser" is a song by the Beatles, originally released on Beatles for Sale in the United Kingdom, later released on Beatles '65 in the United States. Written by John Lennon, (though credited to Lennon–McCartney), it was considered for release as a single until Lennon wrote "I Feel Fine". According to music critic Richie Unterberger, while the lyrics tell a story of romantic rejection, "I'm a Loser" is one of the first Beatles compositions that "goes beyond young love," including "the hypocrisy of keeping up a happy face when your world's falling down".
dbo:abstract | «I’m a Loser» (рус. Я — неудачник) — песня группы «Битлз», вошедшая в четвёртый британский альбом группы Beatles for Sale и в американский альбом Beatles '65. Песня была написана Джоном Ленноном, авторство приписано Ленонну и Маккартни. До того, как Леннон написал композицию «I Feel Fine», песню «I’m a Loser» намеревались выпустить в виде сингла. Согласно музыкальному критику Ричи Антербергеру, несмотря на то, что текст песни повествует об отказе в романтических отношениях, данная песня является одной из первых композиций «Битлз», которая «выходит за рамки юношеской любви», включая «притворное счастливое лицо в то время, когда рушится весь твой мир».
dbo:abstract | 「アイム・ア・ルーザー」 （"I'm A Loser"）はイギリスのロックバンド、ビートルズの楽曲である。
dbo:album | dbr:Beatles_for_Sale
dbo:genre | dbr:Country_music
dbo:genre | dbr:Folk_rock
dbo:musicalArtist | dbr:The_Beatles
dbo:musicalBand | dbr:The_Beatles
dbo:producer | dbr:George_Martin
dbo:recordDate | 1964-08-14
dbo:recordLabel | dbr:EMI
dbo:recordLabel | dbr:Capitol_Records
dbo:recordLabel | dbr:Parlophone
dbo:recordedIn | dbr:Abbey_Road
dbo:releaseDate | 1964-12-04
dbo:runtime | 151.0
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.beatlesbible.com/songs/im-a-loser/
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.icce.rug.nl/~soundscapes/DATABASES/AWP/ial.shtml
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.norwegianwood.org/beatles/disko/uklp/sale.htm
dbo:wikiPageID | 2254732
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 742707797
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eels_(band)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Lead_guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Alan_W._Pollack
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:EMI
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_published_by_Northern_Songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Buck_Owens
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mr._Moonlight_(song)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Lost_Dogs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tambourine
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_George_Martin
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Beatles_'65
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/St._Martin's_Press
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Rock_and_Roll_Music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Beatles
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marianne_Faithfull_(album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Jones
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Bass_guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Leave_My_Kitten_Alone
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Acoustic_guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Harmonica
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Buckinghams
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Martin
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Shaun_Micallef
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Allmusic
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Capitol_Records
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Rhythm_guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Harrison
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Happiness_Is_a_Warm_Gun
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Marianne_Faithfull
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Little_Red_Riding_Hood_(album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:I_Feel_Fine
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lennon–McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Abbey_Road
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Richie_Unterberger
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Vince_Guaraldi
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Eels_(band)_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Live_at_El_Matador
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Harmony_vocal
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Beatles_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Bob_Dylan
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Punkles
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Country_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ringo_Starr
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Lennon–McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Carl_Giammarese
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Parlophone
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Beatles_for_Sale
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ian_MacDonald
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Lead_vocals
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/She's_a_Woman
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Beck_(musician)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Folk_rock
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Sum_41
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Bola_Sete
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Doug_Kershaw
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Dennis_Tufano
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Drum_kit
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:John_Lennon
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Paul_McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Henry_Holt_and_Company
dbo:writer | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lennon–McCartney
dbp:align | left
dbp:cover | I'm_a_Loser.jpg
dbp:quote | Looking back on it I think songs like 'I'm a Loser' and 'Nowhere Man' were John's cries for help. We used to listen to quite a lot of country and western songs and they are all about sadness and 'I lost my truck' so it was quite acceptable to sing 'I'm a loser' ... It's only later you think, God! I think it was brave of John.
dbp:source | Paul McCartney
dbp:trackNo | 2
dbp:width | 21
dbp:wordnet_type | http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-song-noun-1
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_published_by_Northern_Songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Beatles_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Eels_(band)_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Lennon–McCartney
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_George_Martin
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Song
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Song107048000
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatSongsPublishedByNorthernSongs
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Music107020895
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatEels(band)Songs
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Wikicat1964Songs
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Signal106791372
rdf:type | http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/MusicalComposition
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Recording104063661
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatSongRecordingsProducedByGeorgeMartin
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatTheBeatlesSongs
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdf:type | http://schema.org/CreativeWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MusicalComposition107037465
rdf:type | dbo:Single
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AuditoryCommunication107109019
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Abstraction100002137
rdf:type | http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/MusicalComposition_Song
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Communication100033020
rdfs:comment | I'm a Loser Pistes de Beatles for Sale No Reply Baby's in Black I'm a Loser est une chanson des Beatles composée par John Lennon et créditée Lennon/McCartney. Il s'agit de la première chanson véritablement personnelle de Lennon, inspiré par Bob Dylan. Enregistrée en août 1964, elle paraît sur l'album Beatles for Sale (Beatles '65 aux États-Unis). Cette première incursion du groupe dans le registre folk a fait l'objet de quelques reprises. Il s'agit également de la dernière composition des Beatles dans laquelle apparaît un harmonica.
rdfs:comment | 「アイム・ア・ルーザー」 （"I'm A Loser"）はイギリスのロックバンド、ビートルズの楽曲である。
rdfs:comment | I’m a Loser (engl. ‚Ich bin ein Verlierer‘) ist ein Lied der britischen Band The Beatles aus dem Jahr 1964. Komponiert wurde es von John Lennon, es steht jedoch unter dem bei der Band üblichen Copyright Lennon/McCartney.
rdfs:comment | «I’m a Loser» (рус. Я — неудачник) — песня группы «Битлз», вошедшая в четвёртый британский альбом группы Beatles for Sale и в американский альбом Beatles '65. Песня была написана Джоном Ленноном, авторство приписано Ленонну и Маккартни. До того, как Леннон написал композицию «I Feel Fine», песню «I’m a Loser» намеревались выпустить в виде сингла.
rdfs:comment | "I'm a Loser" é uma canção composta por John Lennon e creditada a Lennon/McCartney. Foi gravada pela banda britânica The Beatles e lançada no álbum Beatles for Sale, de 1964.
rdfs:comment | I’m a Loser is een nummer van The Beatles. Het staat op het album Beatles for Sale uit 1964. In het volgende jaar werd het opgenomen op het Amerikaanse album Beatles ’65. Het nummer is geschreven door John Lennon, maar staat, zoals gebruikelijk, op naam van Lennon-McCartney. Er is nog overwogen het nummer op single uit te brengen, maar de eerstvolgende Beatlessingle werd I Feel Fine.
rdfs:comment | "I'm a Loser" is a song by the Beatles, originally released on Beatles for Sale in the United Kingdom, later released on Beatles '65 in the United States. Written by John Lennon, (though credited to Lennon–McCartney), it was considered for release as a single until Lennon wrote "I Feel Fine". According to music critic Richie Unterberger, while the lyrics tell a story of romantic rejection, "I'm a Loser" is one of the first Beatles compositions that "goes beyond young love," including "the hypocrisy of keeping up a happy face when your world's falling down".
rdfs:comment | I'm a Loser è un brano dei Beatles, contenuto nell'album Beatles for Sale del 1964. È stata scritta prevalentemente da John Lennon ed accreditata al duo Lennon/McCartney.
rdfs:comment | "I'm a Loser" es una canción de The Beatles lanzada originalmente en el álbum Beatles for Sale. Estaba previsto que saliera como un sencillo en el Reino Unido hasta que John Lennon escribiera "I Feel Fine". En la primera edición de Beatles for Sale, la canción fue erróneamente impresa como "I'm a Losser".
rdfs:label | アイム・ア・ルーザー
rdfs:label | I’m a Loser
rdfs:label | I’m a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
rdfs:label | I'm a Loser
owl:sameAs | http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/I’m_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/アイム・ア・ルーザー
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.06zkym
owl:sameAs | http://nl.dbpedia.org/resource/I'm_a_Loser
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I'm_a_Loser?oldid=742707797
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I'm_a_Loser
foaf:name | I'm a Loser

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: http://dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(Muse_song)
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Manifestation

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | "Psycho" is a song by the English rock band Muse from their seventh studio album Drones, released on 12 March 2015 as a promotional single. It was later featured as the B-side to the official lead single later that month, "Dead Inside".
dbo:abstract | Psycho est la troisième piste de l'album Drones de Muse parue le 12 mars 2015. Il s'agit du premier extrait dévoilé de l'album mais n'est pas un single à part entière. La date de la première diffusion est annoncée la veille sur le site officiel du groupe lors de l'annonce de l'album. Le morceau est offert au moment de la précommande de l'album le 12 mars 2015 à 19 h 30 (GMT). Il sort dans les bacs en disque physique en tant que face B du single Dead Inside, le 12 mai 2015. Il s'agit du premier single physique depuis 2010.
dbo:abstract | "Psycho" é uma canção da banda britânica de rock Muse, que esta no seu sétimo álbum intitulado Drones. Foi liberado pela primeira vez em 12 de março de 2015 como o primeiro single promocional do disco. Mais tarde ele foi lançado como um b-side da música "Dead Inside".
dbo:abstract | Psycho is een nummer van de Britse rockband Muse, afkomstig van hun zevende studioalbum Drones. Het nummer werd op 12 maart 2015 uitgebracht als promotiesingle en verscheen later als b-kant van de single Dead Inside. De basisriff van het nummer werd voor het eerst gespeeld in 1999 en was ook te horen op de HAARP-concertregistratie. Volgens zanger en gitarist Matthew Bellamy is het nummer te aanstootgevend om op de radio te worden gedraaid. Het Nederlandse radiostation NPO 3FM riep het nummer op 20 maart 2015 uit tot 3FM Megahit.
dbo:abstract | Psycho è un singolo promozionale del gruppo musicale britannico Muse, estratto dal settimo album in studio Drones e pubblicato il 12 marzo 2015.
dbo:album | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Drones_(Muse_album)
dbo:artist | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Muse_(band)
dbo:genre | dbr:Hard_rock
dbo:genre | dbr:Glam_rock
dbo:producer | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Muse_(band)
dbo:producer | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Robert_John_%22Mutt%22_Lange
dbo:recordLabel | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Helium_3_(record_label)
dbo:recordLabel | dbr:Warner_Bros._Records
dbo:releaseDate | 2015-03-12
dbo:subsequentWork | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mercy_(Muse_song)
dbo:trackNumber | 3
dbo:type | dbr:Promotional_single
dbo:wikiPageID | 45657779
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 735775813
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Muse_(band)_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Matthew_Bellamy
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Official_Charts_Company
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:NME
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Warner_Bros._Records
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Music_video
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Narrative
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Muse_(band)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Promotional_single
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Drones_(Muse_album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:A-side_and_B-side
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dead_Inside_(song)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Warehouse_Studio
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Anti-war_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Instagram
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_Robert_John_%22Mutt%22_Lange
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Dubstep
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Matthew_Bellamy
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Twitter
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Vancouver
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Music_download
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:CD_single
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Audio_mixing_(recorded_music)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:British_Columbia
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Kate_Hudson
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:YouTube
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Robert_John_%22Mutt%22_Lange
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Rock_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/HAARP_(album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Mind_control
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Billboard_(magazine)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Hard_rock
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Glam_rock
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mercy_(Muse_song)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_2nd_Law
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2015_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Helium_3_(record_label)
dbo:writer | dbr:Matthew_Bellamy
dbp:aSide | "Dead Inside"
dbp:cover | Psycho - Muse.jpg
dbp:format | dbr:CD_single
dbp:format | dbr:Music_download
dbp:headline | CD single
dbp:length | 328.0
dbp:length | 263.0
dbp:nextNo | 4
dbp:prev | "[Drill Sergeant]"
dbp:prevNo | 2
dbp:title | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dead_Inside_(song)
dbp:title | Psycho
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2015_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Muse_(band)_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Matthew_Bellamy
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_Robert_John_%22Mutt%22_Lange
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Anti-war_songs
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Song
rdf:type | http://schema.org/MusicRecording
rdf:type | dbo:Song
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | dbo:Single
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdf:type | http://schema.org/CreativeWork
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdfs:comment | Psycho est la troisième piste de l'album Drones de Muse parue le 12 mars 2015. Il s'agit du premier extrait dévoilé de l'album mais n'est pas un single à part entière. La date de la première diffusion est annoncée la veille sur le site officiel du groupe lors de l'annonce de l'album. Le morceau est offert au moment de la précommande de l'album le 12 mars 2015 à 19 h 30 (GMT). Il sort dans les bacs en disque physique en tant que face B du single Dead Inside, le 12 mai 2015. Il s'agit du premier single physique depuis 2010.
rdfs:comment | Psycho è un singolo promozionale del gruppo musicale britannico Muse, estratto dal settimo album in studio Drones e pubblicato il 12 marzo 2015.
rdfs:comment | Psycho is een nummer van de Britse rockband Muse, afkomstig van hun zevende studioalbum Drones. Het nummer werd op 12 maart 2015 uitgebracht als promotiesingle en verscheen later als b-kant van de single Dead Inside. De basisriff van het nummer werd voor het eerst gespeeld in 1999 en was ook te horen op de HAARP-concertregistratie. Volgens zanger en gitarist Matthew Bellamy is het nummer te aanstootgevend om op de radio te worden gedraaid. Het Nederlandse radiostation NPO 3FM riep het nummer op 20 maart 2015 uit tot 3FM Megahit.
rdfs:comment | "Psycho" é uma canção da banda britânica de rock Muse, que esta no seu sétimo álbum intitulado Drones. Foi liberado pela primeira vez em 12 de março de 2015 como o primeiro single promocional do disco. Mais tarde ele foi lançado como um b-side da música "Dead Inside".
rdfs:comment | "Psycho" is a song by the English rock band Muse from their seventh studio album Drones, released on 12 March 2015 as a promotional single. It was later featured as the B-side to the official lead single later that month, "Dead Inside".
rdfs:label | Psycho (chanson de Muse)
rdfs:label | Psycho (Muse)
rdfs:label | Psycho (Muse)
rdfs:label | Psycho (canção de Muse)
rdfs:label | Psycho (Muse song)
owl:sameAs | http://nl.dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(Muse)
owl:sameAs | http://id.dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(lagu_Muse)
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0130rpmt
owl:sameAs | http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(Muse)
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(chanson_de_Muse)
owl:sameAs | http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Psycho_(canção_de_Muse)
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psycho_(Muse_song)?oldid=735775813
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psycho_(Muse_song)
foaf:name | Psycho

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: dbr:The_Baluch
Example of http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Work

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | The Baluch is a composition by Iranian composer Mehdi Hosseini for six instruments, written in 2009. It is in three movements and inspired by Persian folk music. It is one of the first works of Hosseini's total minimalism work. It was premiered on 11 June 2009 at the Saint Petersburg House of Composers. This performance was given by selected soloists from the St. Petersburg State Conservatory and the St. Petersburg Philharmonic Orchestra, and was conducted by Brad Cawyer, an American conductor based in Saint Petersburg. There are three movements: 1. * Liku Dalgani 2. * Kalampour 3. * Zoljalal-Guati
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.tehrantimes.com/index_View.asp?code=196271
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://epoch-archive.com/a1/en/us/was/2009/06-Jun/11/B2_EET20090611-DCUS.pdf
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://payvand.com/news/09/oct/1231.html
dbo:wikiPageID | 25498806
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 744930824
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Minimalism
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2009_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Mehdi_Hosseini
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Saint_Petersburg
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Minimalistic_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:United_States
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:21st-century_classical_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Iran
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Musical_conductor
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Persian_folk_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:St._Petersburg_State_Conservatory
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Composer
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:St._Petersburg_Philharmonic_Orchestra
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Mehdi_Hosseini
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Minimalistic_compositions
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:21st-century_classical_music
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:2009_compositions
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Mehdi_Hosseini
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Composition
rdf:type | http://schema.org/CreativeWork
rdf:type | dbo:ClassicalMusicComposition
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdfs:comment | The Baluch is a composition by Iranian composer Mehdi Hosseini for six instruments, written in 2009. It is in three movements and inspired by Persian folk music. It is one of the first works of Hosseini's total minimalism work. It was premiered on 11 June 2009 at the Saint Petersburg House of Composers. This performance was given by selected soloists from the St. Petersburg State Conservatory and the St. Petersburg Philharmonic Orchestra, and was conducted by Brad Cawyer, an American conductor based in Saint Petersburg. There are three movements:
rdfs:label | The Baluch
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.09rvmz9
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Baluch?oldid=744930824
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Baluch

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Consecration_of_the_House_(overture)
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Work

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | Ludwig van Beethovens Begleitmusik zu Die Weihe des Hauses ist eine Adaption seines früheren Werks Die Ruinen von Athen, op. 113. Anlässlich der Neueröffnung des Josefstädter Theaters in Wien am 3. Oktober 1822 passte Marinekriegskommissär Karl Meisl das Festspiel Die Ruinen von Athen von August von Kotzebue an. Es entstand Die Weihe des Hauses. Meisl änderte dabei den Text, sodass die bisherige Musik Beethovens nicht vollständig zum Text passte, und ergänzte den Text Wo sich die Pulse, für den Beethoven eine neue Komposition erarbeitete (WoO 98).An der übrigen Begleitmusik änderte Beethoven wenig, fügte aber einen Schlusschor mit Violinsolo und Ballett ein, überarbeitete einen Marsch (op. 114) undschrieb die neue Ouvertüre (op. 124), da die ursprüngliche Ouvertüre als Nachstück nicht angemessen war. Es war das erste Werk Beethovens, nachdem er seine Studien von J. S. Bach und Georg Friedrich Händel abgeschlossen hatte, und ist daher stark von diesen beeinflusst. Beethoven widmete die Ouvertüre dem Fürsten Nikolaus von Galitzin.
dbo:abstract | The Consecration of the House (or Die Weihe des Hauses), Op. 124, is a work by Ludwig van Beethoven composed in September 1822. It was commissioned by Carl Friedrich Hensler, the Director of Vienna's new Theater in der Josefstadt, and was first performed at the theatre's opening on October 3, 1822. It was the first work Beethoven wrote after his revival of studying the works of J. S. Bach and Handel, and bears their influence. Previously, in 1811, Beethoven had written The Ruins of Athens (Die Ruinen von Athen), Op. 113, incidental music for August von Kotzebue's play of the same name, for the dedication of a new theatre in Pest. This same work was to be performed again in 1822 for the new theatre in Vienna. However, Carl Meisl, the commissioner of the Royal Imperial Navy, changed the texts of numbers 1, 6, 7, and 8 of Beethoven's work. Beethoven was not pleased with the revision, and felt that the new text did not fit the music. Meisl also introduced a section, Wo sich die Pulse, for which Beethoven wrote new music (WoO 98). Beethoven wrote a completely new overture for the work, altered some of the musical numbers, and added others, including a final chorus with violin solo and ballet. This new overture is known as the The Consecration of the House Overture. (The extra incidental pieces constitute the entire work.)
dbo:abstract | A Consagração da Casa (em alemão: Die Weihe des Hauses) é uma obra musical escrita por Ludwig van Beethoven em 1822 para a inauguração do Theater in der Josefstadt em Viena, que ocorreu em 3 de outubro do mesmo ano. Relatos de Anton Felix Schindler - um dos primeiros biógrafos de Beethoven - descrevem um passeio, no qual Beethoven parou para escrever dois temas para a abertura. "Ele explicou que estava planejando desenvolver um deles livremente e o outro no estilo formal de Händel […] há muito tempo ele acalentava a ideia de escrever uma abertura especificamente no estilo de Handel". Na composição como conhecemos hoje não pode ser observado o desenvolvimento livre de tema, mas nota-se a presença de elementos handelianos. A obra foi composta como se fosse um grande prelúdio e fuga. Inicia-se com uma ampla e nobre melodia de marcha, tocada inicialmente pelas madeiras com acompanhamento de pizzicato e contrabaixo suave. A segunda seção é marcada pela entrada dos trompetes com bastante brilho, acompanhados pelo moto perpetuo dos fagotes executado em semicolcheias. A última seção é um fugato que acaba encaminhando ao alegro principal. A Consagração da Casa é considerada como a melhor dentre as últimas aberturas de Beethoven e mostra como poderiam ser os oratórios e concertos que ele pretendia escrever ao estilo de Händel.
dbo:abstract | Die Weihe des HausesDie Weihe des Hauses op. 124 (La Consécration de la maison ou L’Inauguration de la maison en français) est une ouverture en ut majeur de Ludwig van Beethoven composée en septembre 1822 pour répondre à une commande du directeur du théâtre de la Josefstadt qui allait inaugurer son théâtre. Composée dans la période particulière qui séparait la composition de la Missa Solemnis de celle de la Symphonie no 9, La Consécration de la maison est la dernière ouverture écrite par Beethoven. Le compositeur la voulait « dans le style strict de Haendel », mais il reconnut quelque temps plus tard ne pas avoir atteint pleinement son objectif, si ce n’est dans la majestueuse introduction. L’ouverture fut créée le 3 octobre 1822 et rejouée au concert du 7 mai 1824 où furent créées la Missa Solemnis et la Symphonie no 9. Elle reste assez rarement jouée de nos jours.
dbo:abstract | 献堂式序曲（Ouvertüre „Die Weihe des Hauses“）作品124は、ルートヴィヒ・ヴァン・ベートーヴェンが作曲した序曲である。ベートーヴェンが、純粋管弦楽のために作曲した最後の作品にあたり、1820年代に書かれた唯一の序曲でもある。また祝典劇の『献堂式』も解説する。
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.answers.com/topic/die-weihe-des-hauses-consecration-of-the-house-overture-for-orchestra-op-124
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.musicwithease.com/consecration-house.html
dbo:wikiPageID | 4842760
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 744179660
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Johann_Sebastian_Bach
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Anton_Schindler
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ludwig_van_Beethoven
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Theater_in_der_Josefstadt
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Frideric_Handel
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Joseph_Haydn
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Counterpoint
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:August_von_Kotzebue
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1822_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Ruins_of_Athens
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Incidental_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Overtures
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Vienna
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Modulation_(music)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Fugue
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Ludwig_van_Beethoven
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pest,_Hungary
dbp:cname | The Consecration of the House Overture
dbp:cname | Wo sich die Pulse
dbp:work | Die Weihe des Hauses, Op.124
dbp:work | Wo sich die Pulse, WoO 98
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Ludwig_van_Beethoven
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1822_compositions
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Overtures
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Music107020895
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Overture107040820
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatOvertures
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Communication100033020
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Abstraction100002137
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AuditoryCommunication107109019
rdfs:comment | The Consecration of the House (or Die Weihe des Hauses), Op. 124, is a work by Ludwig van Beethoven composed in September 1822. It was commissioned by Carl Friedrich Hensler, the Director of Vienna's new Theater in der Josefstadt, and was first performed at the theatre's opening on October 3, 1822. It was the first work Beethoven wrote after his revival of studying the works of J. S. Bach and Handel, and bears their influence.
rdfs:comment | Die Weihe des HausesDie Weihe des Hauses op. 124 (La Consécration de la maison ou L’Inauguration de la maison en français) est une ouverture en ut majeur de Ludwig van Beethoven composée en septembre 1822 pour répondre à une commande du directeur du théâtre de la Josefstadt qui allait inaugurer son théâtre. L’ouverture fut créée le 3 octobre 1822 et rejouée au concert du 7 mai 1824 où furent créées la Missa Solemnis et la Symphonie no 9. Elle reste assez rarement jouée de nos jours.
rdfs:comment | A Consagração da Casa (em alemão: Die Weihe des Hauses) é uma obra musical escrita por Ludwig van Beethoven em 1822 para a inauguração do Theater in der Josefstadt em Viena, que ocorreu em 3 de outubro do mesmo ano. A Consagração da Casa é considerada como a melhor dentre as últimas aberturas de Beethoven e mostra como poderiam ser os oratórios e concertos que ele pretendia escrever ao estilo de Händel.
rdfs:comment | Ludwig van Beethovens Begleitmusik zu Die Weihe des Hauses ist eine Adaption seines früheren Werks Die Ruinen von Athen, op. 113. Anlässlich der Neueröffnung des Josefstädter Theaters in Wien am 3. Oktober 1822 passte Marinekriegskommissär Karl Meisl das Festspiel Die Ruinen von Athen von August von Kotzebue an. Es entstand Die Weihe des Hauses. Meisl änderte dabei den Text, sodass die bisherige Musik Beethovens nicht vollständig zum Text passte, und ergänzte den Text Wo sich die Pulse, für den Beethoven eine neue Komposition erarbeitete (WoO 98).An der übrigen Begleitmusik änderte Beethoven wenig, fügte aber einen Schlusschor mit Violinsolo und Ballett ein, überarbeitete einen Marsch (op. 114) undschrieb die neue Ouvertüre (op. 124), da die ursprüngliche Ouvertüre als Nachstück nicht ange
rdfs:comment | 献堂式序曲（Ouvertüre „Die Weihe des Hauses“）作品124は、ルートヴィヒ・ヴァン・ベートーヴェンが作曲した序曲である。ベートーヴェンが、純粋管弦楽のために作曲した最後の作品にあたり、1820年代に書かれた唯一の序曲でもある。また祝典劇の『献堂式』も解説する。
rdfs:label | A Consagração da Casa
rdfs:label | The Consecration of the House (overture)
rdfs:label | La Consécration de la maison
rdfs:label | 献堂式序曲
rdfs:label | Die Weihe des Hauses
owl:sameAs | http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Die_Weihe_des_Hauses
owl:sameAs | http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/The_Consecration_of_the_House_(overture)
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0cqjbf
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/La_Consécration_de_la_maison
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/献堂式序曲
owl:sameAs | http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/A_Consagração_da_Casa
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Consecration_of_the_House_(overture)?oldid=744179660
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Consecration_of_the_House_(overture)

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Work
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Expression
example 6 - Manifestation
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Expression
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Expression
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Manifestation

You are currently annotating resource: http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Music_Makers_(Elgar)
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Work

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | The Music Makers, Op. 69, est une œuvre pour contralto ou mezzo-soprano, chœurs et orchestre composé par Edward Elgar. Cette pièce est dédiée à « my friend Nicholas Kilburn ». Elle est créée lors du Festival de Birmingham le 1 octobre 1912, dirigée par le compositeur avec comme soliste Muriel Foster (en). Le texte est une ode de 1874 d'Arthur O'Shaughnessy qu'Elgar met entièrement en musique. Elgar travaille sur ce morceau par intermittence depuis 1903, sans commande particulière.
dbo:abstract | The Music Makers, Op. 69, is a work for contralto or mezzo-soprano, chorus and orchestra composed by Edward Elgar. It was dedicated to "my friend Nicholas Kilburn". It was first performed at the Birmingham Festival on 1 October 1912, conducted by the composer, with Muriel Foster as the soloist. The text of the work is the 1874 poem Ode by Arthur O'Shaughnessy, which Elgar set in its entirety. He had been working on the music intermittently since 1903, without a specific commission.
dbo:abstract | 『ミュージック・メイカーズ』（The Music Makers）作品69は、エドワード・エルガーが作曲したコントラルトまたはメゾソプラノと合唱、管弦楽のための作品。「我が友ニコラス・キルバーン」へ献呈された。初演は1912年10月1日に作曲者自身の指揮、マリエル・フォスターの独唱により、バーミンガム・トリエンナーレ音楽祭で行われた。 テクストはアーサー・オショーネシーの『Ode』（1874年）から採られており、曲には詩の全文が用いられている。作曲は委嘱を受ける以前の1903年から断続的に行われていた。
dbo:wikiPageID | 1804805
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 744184834
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Edward_Elgar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ein_Heldenleben
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Choir
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Janet_Baker
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Enigma_Variations
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Edward_Elgar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:La_Marseillaise
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Choralwiki:The_Music_Makers,_Op._69_(Edward_Elgar)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Mezzo-soprano
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Muriel_Foster
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Arthur_O'Shaughnessy
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1912_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:London_Philharmonic_Orchestra
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Sea_Pictures
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Hallé
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:London_Philharmonic_Choir
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Symphony_No._2_(Elgar)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Jean_Rigby
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:BBC_Symphony_Orchestra
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Violin_Concerto_(Elgar)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rule,_Britannia!
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Dream_of_Gerontius
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Musical_quotation
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Andrew_Davis_(conductor)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Birmingham_Triennial_Music_Festival
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Choral_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Symphony_No._1_(Elgar)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Richard_Strauss
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Choral_Public_Domain_Library
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Three_Choirs_Festival
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ode_(poem)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Contralto
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Orchestra
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Adrian_Boult
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Mark_Elder
dbp:class | composition
dbp:cname | The Music Makers
dbp:first | Wayne
dbp:id | mc0002367358
dbp:label | The Music Makers
dbp:last | Reisig
dbp:work | The_Music_Makers,_Op.69_
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Compositions_by_Edward_Elgar
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Choral_compositions
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1912_compositions
rdfs:comment | The Music Makers, Op. 69, est une œuvre pour contralto ou mezzo-soprano, chœurs et orchestre composé par Edward Elgar. Cette pièce est dédiée à « my friend Nicholas Kilburn ». Elle est créée lors du Festival de Birmingham le 1 octobre 1912, dirigée par le compositeur avec comme soliste Muriel Foster (en). Le texte est une ode de 1874 d'Arthur O'Shaughnessy qu'Elgar met entièrement en musique. Elgar travaille sur ce morceau par intermittence depuis 1903, sans commande particulière.
rdfs:comment | The Music Makers, Op. 69, is a work for contralto or mezzo-soprano, chorus and orchestra composed by Edward Elgar. It was dedicated to "my friend Nicholas Kilburn". It was first performed at the Birmingham Festival on 1 October 1912, conducted by the composer, with Muriel Foster as the soloist. The text of the work is the 1874 poem Ode by Arthur O'Shaughnessy, which Elgar set in its entirety. He had been working on the music intermittently since 1903, without a specific commission.
rdfs:comment | 『ミュージック・メイカーズ』（The Music Makers）作品69は、エドワード・エルガーが作曲したコントラルトまたはメゾソプラノと合唱、管弦楽のための作品。「我が友ニコラス・キルバーン」へ献呈された。初演は1912年10月1日に作曲者自身の指揮、マリエル・フォスターの独唱により、バーミンガム・トリエンナーレ音楽祭で行われた。 テクストはアーサー・オショーネシーの『Ode』（1874年）から採られており、曲には詩の全文が用いられている。作曲は委嘱を受ける以前の1903年から断続的に行われていた。
rdfs:label | ミュージック・メイカーズ (エルガー)
rdfs:label | The Music Makers
rdfs:label | The Music Makers (Elgar)
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.05ybj8
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Music_Makers
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ミュージック・メイカーズ_(エルガー)
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Music_Makers_(Elgar)?oldid=744184834
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Music_Makers_(Elgar)

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Expression
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Manifestation
example 6 - Expression
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Work
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Manifestation
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Expression

You are currently annotating resource: dbr:Twelfth_Street_Rag
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Work

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | 12番街のラグ Twelfth Street Rag（じゅうにばんがいのラグ）は1914年にユーディ・L・ボウマン（Euday L. Bowman）が作曲したラグタイム曲。曲名はボウマンが出演していたカンザスシティの盛り場「12番街」から採られている。ラグタイム時代にとりわけ有名なベスト・セラーとなった曲である。ルイ・アームストロングからレスター・ヤングまで、多くの様々なアーティスト達が録音してきていて、現在もディキシーランド・ジャズのスタンダード・ナンバーとなっている。 ピー・ウィー・ハント（Pee Wee Hunt）のピアノ録音はビルボードの1948年のナンバー・ワン・シングルとなり、300万枚を超す売り上げとなった。これはCapitol Records 15015として同年の3月に売り出されたものである。 作曲者ユーディ・L・ボウマン自身もこの曲を録音して Bowman 11748 として出版した。 この曲の楽式は、「イントロ A A1 イントロ2 A2」である。 この曲は「ジョー・フランクリン・ショー」（the Joe Franklin Show）のテーマ曲として最もよく知られている。 1919年のチャーリー・チャップリンによる短編映画『一日の行楽』では、乗船中のシーンで、アフリカ系アメリカ人のバンドがこの曲のポピュラー・ラグのバージョンを演奏しているのを聴くことができる。 さらに最近では、テレビ・シリーズ『スポンジ・ボブ/スクエアパンツ』のバックグラウンド・ミュージックで、ウクレレのバージョンがよく用いられている。
dbo:abstract | "Twelfth Street Rag" is a ragtime musical composition published by Euday L. Bowman in 1914. Years earlier, a friend of Bowman's known only as "Raggedy Ed" declared his intention to open a pawn shop on 12th Street while the two were walking along it. Bowman is rumored to have said "If you get rich on those three balls, I'll write a piece on three notes to make myself rich." The result was "The 12th Street Rag," one of the most famous and best-selling rags of the ragtime era. It was more than 15 years after Bowman composed the song before he actually wrote the music down in manuscript form. He returned to Texas briefly and tried to sell the piece to a company in Dallas; but he only had an offer of ten dollars for it and was told it really wasn't worth publishing. Returning to Kansas City, he sold it to Jenkins Music Company in 1913. The Jenkins company felt Bowman's arrangement was too difficult, however, and hired C. E. Wheeler to simplify it. With a big advertising push, "12th Street Rag" began to sell better. In 1919, James S. Sumner added lyrics. The song was popular with early Kansas City bands and became a huge hit after Bennie Moten recorded it for RCA Victor in 1927, the same year that Louis Armstrong and His Hot Seven recorded it. It has since become an enduring jazz standard.
dbo:abstract | Twelfth Street Rag (Ragtime Dwunastej Ulicy) – ragtime skomponowany w r. 1914 przez Euday L. Bowmana, Teksańczyka pracującego w Nowym Jorku. Utwór wykonywało wielu artystów, m.in. Louis Armstrong i Lester Young. Kompozytor sprzedał prawa do utworu firmie Jenkins Music Company za sto dolarów w r. 1948, długo po tym, jak utwór stał się wielkim przebojem.
dbo:thumbnail | http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/12thStreetRag1915.jpg?width=300
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=waQt1SztQWQ
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://laurel.lso.missouri.edu/record=b5199034~S3
dbo:wikiPageID | 11824973
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 738108206
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Pee_Wee_Hunt
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Louis_Armstrong_and_His_Hot_Seven
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Best_Sellers_in_Stores
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:List_of_pre-1920_jazz_standards
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Bennie_Moten
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Okeh_Records
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Billboard_(magazine)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Euday_L._Bowman
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/File:Twelfth_Street_Rag.ogg
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1914_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Donald_Peers
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:EMI
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Big_Tiny_Little
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Solo_piano_pieces
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1910s_jazz_standards
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Buttons_and_Bows
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/His_Master's_Voice
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/File:12thStreetRag1915.jpg
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_English_Patient_(film)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Rags
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ukulele
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/You_Call_Everybody_Darlin'
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Al_Trace
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:A_Tree_in_the_Meadow
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_number-one_hits_(United_States)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Bandmaster_(1930_cartoon)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Dinah_Shore
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Brunswick_Records
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Background_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ragtime
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:SpongeBob_SquarePants
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Krazy_Kat
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Margaret_Whiting
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Joe_Franklin
dbp:after | "Buttons and Bows" by Dinah Shore
dbp:after | "A Tree in the Meadow" by Margaret Whiting
dbp:before | "A Tree in the Meadow" by Margaret Whiting
dbp:before | "You Call Everybody Darlin'" by Al Trace
dbp:title | U.S. Billboard Best Sellers in Stores number-one single
dbp:years | --08-28
dbp:years | --10-23
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Solo_piano_pieces
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Rags
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1910s_jazz_standards
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1914_compositions
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatJazzStandards
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Abstraction100002137
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Music107020895
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Wikicat1910sJazzStandards
rdf:type | http://schema.org/CreativeWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Communication100033020
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Song107048000
rdf:type | dbo:Song
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Standard107260623
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MusicalComposition107037465
rdf:type | http://schema.org/MusicRecording
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/SystemOfMeasurement113577171
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Measure100033615
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AuditoryCommunication107109019
rdfs:comment | Twelfth Street Rag (Ragtime Dwunastej Ulicy) – ragtime skomponowany w r. 1914 przez Euday L. Bowmana, Teksańczyka pracującego w Nowym Jorku. Utwór wykonywało wielu artystów, m.in. Louis Armstrong i Lester Young. Kompozytor sprzedał prawa do utworu firmie Jenkins Music Company za sto dolarów w r. 1948, długo po tym, jak utwór stał się wielkim przebojem.
rdfs:comment | 12番街のラグ Twelfth Street Rag（じゅうにばんがいのラグ）は1914年にユーディ・L・ボウマン（Euday L. Bowman）が作曲したラグタイム曲。曲名はボウマンが出演していたカンザスシティの盛り場「12番街」から採られている。ラグタイム時代にとりわけ有名なベスト・セラーとなった曲である。ルイ・アームストロングからレスター・ヤングまで、多くの様々なアーティスト達が録音してきていて、現在もディキシーランド・ジャズのスタンダード・ナンバーとなっている。 ピー・ウィー・ハント（Pee Wee Hunt）のピアノ録音はビルボードの1948年のナンバー・ワン・シングルとなり、300万枚を超す売り上げとなった。これはCapitol Records 15015として同年の3月に売り出されたものである。 作曲者ユーディ・L・ボウマン自身もこの曲を録音して Bowman 11748 として出版した。 この曲の楽式は、「イントロ A A1 イントロ2 A2」である。 この曲は「ジョー・フランクリン・ショー」（the Joe Franklin Show）のテーマ曲として最もよく知られている。 1919年のチャーリー・チャップリンによる短編映画『一日の行楽』では、乗船中のシーンで、アフリカ系アメリカ人のバンドがこの曲のポピュラー・ラグのバージョンを演奏しているのを聴くことができる。
rdfs:comment | "Twelfth Street Rag" is a ragtime musical composition published by Euday L. Bowman in 1914. Years earlier, a friend of Bowman's known only as "Raggedy Ed" declared his intention to open a pawn shop on 12th Street while the two were walking along it. Bowman is rumored to have said "If you get rich on those three balls, I'll write a piece on three notes to make myself rich." The result was "The 12th Street Rag," one of the most famous and best-selling rags of the ragtime era.
rdfs:label | Twelfth Street Rag
rdfs:label | Twelfth Street Rag
rdfs:label | 12番街のラグ
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/12番街のラグ
owl:sameAs | http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Twelfth_Street_Rag
owl:sameAs | http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Twelfth_Street_Rag
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.02rtrwp
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twelfth_Street_Rag?oldid=738108206
foaf:depiction | http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/12thStreetRag1915.jpg
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twelfth_Street_Rag

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Work
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Expression
example 6 - Manifestation
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Expression
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Expression
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Manifestation

You are currently annotating resource: dbr:Ymarxa
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Work

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
dbo:abstract | Ymarxa is an orchestral piece of classical music by the Spanish composer and pianist Gustavo Díaz-Jerez. Ymarxa is a guanche word meaning 'new', 'brilliant', 'splendid'. It also referred to a place in Tenerife in what today is La Esperanza forest. Together with Ayssuragan, Aranfaybo, Azaenegue, Tinaguache, Chigaday, and Erbane, Ymarxa is part of a cycle of seven orchestral works inspired in different places of each of the Canary Islands. Ymarxa was commissioned by the XXVII Festival de Música de Canarias and given its first performance on February 12, 2011 at the Alfredo Kraus Auditorium in Gran Canaria by the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra under maestro Charles Dutoit. It was well received by audience and critics alike. Ymarxa is a one-movement work lasting about 20 minutes, merging elements from spectralism and algorithmic procedures.
dbo:abstract | Ymarxa es una obra orquestal de música clásica del compositor y pianista español Gustavo Díaz Jerez. Ymarxa es una palabra guanche que significa 'nuevo', 'brillante', 'espléndido'. También se refiere a un lugar de Tenerife en lo que hoy es el bosque de La Esperanza. Ymarxa fue encargada por el XXVII Festival de Música de Canarias y fue estrenada el 12 de febrero de 2011 en el Auditorio Alfredo Kraus en Gran Canaria por la Royal Philharmonic Orchestra con el maestro Charles Dutoit. Fue bien recibida por el público y la crítica. Ymarxa se desarrolla en un solo movimiento de unos 20 minutos de duración. Fusiona elementos del espectralismo y la música algorítmica.
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p6U3EYmAmeo
dbo:wikiPageID | 31350103
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 726310922
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Guanche_language
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Spain
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Tenerife
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Chigaday
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Charles_Dutoit
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Erbane
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Aranfaybo
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tinaguache
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Gustavo_Díaz-Jerez
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Pianist
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Contemporary_classical_compositions
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ayssuragan
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Azaenegue
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Gran_Canaria
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Algorithmic_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Royal_Philharmonic_Orchestra
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Spectral_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tenerife
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:European_classical_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Composer
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Contemporary_classical_compositions
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Tenerife
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Piece
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdfs:comment | Ymarxa es una obra orquestal de música clásica del compositor y pianista español Gustavo Díaz Jerez. Ymarxa es una palabra guanche que significa 'nuevo', 'brillante', 'espléndido'. También se refiere a un lugar de Tenerife en lo que hoy es el bosque de La Esperanza. Ymarxa fue encargada por el XXVII Festival de Música de Canarias y fue estrenada el 12 de febrero de 2011 en el Auditorio Alfredo Kraus en Gran Canaria por la Royal Philharmonic Orchestra con el maestro Charles Dutoit. Fue bien recibida por el público y la crítica. Ymarxa se desarrolla en un solo movimiento de unos 20 minutos de duración. Fusiona elementos del espectralismo y la música algorítmica.
rdfs:comment | Ymarxa is an orchestral piece of classical music by the Spanish composer and pianist Gustavo Díaz-Jerez. Ymarxa is a guanche word meaning 'new', 'brilliant', 'splendid'. It also referred to a place in Tenerife in what today is La Esperanza forest. Together with Ayssuragan, Aranfaybo, Azaenegue, Tinaguache, Chigaday, and Erbane, Ymarxa is part of a cycle of seven orchestral works inspired in different places of each of the Canary Islands. Ymarxa was commissioned by the XXVII Festival de Música de Canarias and given its first performance on February 12, 2011 at the Alfredo Kraus Auditorium in Gran Canaria by the Royal Philharmonic Orchestra under maestro Charles Dutoit. It was well received by audience and critics alike. Ymarxa is a one-movement work lasting about 20 minutes, merging element
rdfs:label | Ymarxa
rdfs:label | Ymarxa
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0gkxd4w
owl:sameAs | http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Ymarxa
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ymarxa?oldid=726310922
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ymarxa

DBpedia annotator

When you are ready to start annotating DBpedia resources, feel free to continue back to the application page.

example 1 - Work
example 2 - Work
example 3 - Work
example 4 - Manifestation
example 5 - Expression
example 6 - Manifestation
example 7 - Manifestation
example 8 - Expression
example 9 - Work
example 10 - Work
example 11 - Work
example 12 - Expression
example 13 - Work
example 14 - Work
example 15 - Manifestation
example 16 - Work
example 17 - Manifestation

You are currently annotating resource: dbr:You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
Example of: http://vocab.org/frbr/core.html#term-Manifestation

DBpedia predicate | DBpedia object
http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Work/runtime | 4.033333333333333
dbo:abstract | „You Never Give Me Your Money” – utwór autorstwa Paula McCartneya, nagrany przez brytyjską grupę The Beatles. Piosenka znalazła się na albumie Abbey Road, wydanym w 1969 roku. Utwór rozpoczyna 16. minutowe zestawienie utworów nazwane „Abbey Road Medley”.
dbo:abstract | You Never Give Me Your Money è un brano dei Beatles, scritto soprattutto da Paul McCartney ma accreditato, per convenzione, alla coppia Lennon-McCartney. Compare nell'LP Abbey Road, ed è posta all'inizio del long medley, che caratterizza la seconda facciata dell'album.
dbo:abstract | "You Never Give Me Your Money" is a song by the Beatles, appearing on their 1969 album Abbey Road. It was written by Paul McCartney (though credited to Lennon–McCartney) and documented the financial and personal difficulties facing the band. The track is the first track of the medley on side two of Abbey Road and was recorded in stages between May and August 1969. The song was the first one to be recorded for the medley, which was conceived by McCartney and producer George Martin as a finale for the Beatles' career. The backing track was recorded at Olympic Sound Studios in Barnes, London, but the remainder of overdubs occurred at Abbey Road Studios. Musically, the song is made up of a suite of various segments, ranging from a piano ballad at the beginning through to guitar arpeggios at the end.
dbo:abstract | ユー・ネヴァー・ギヴ・ミー・ユア・マネー(You Never Give Me Your Money)は、1969年に発表されたビートルズのアルバム『アビイ・ロード』に収録されたポール・マッカートニー作の曲でここから同アルバムのB面の特徴であるメドレーに入る。
dbo:abstract | "You Never Give Me Your Money" es una canción de The Beatles que abre el medley culminante en el lado B del álbum Abbey Road. Fue escrita por Paul McCartney aunque atribuida como Lennon/McCartney. McCartney se inspiró al escribir esta canción en los problemas económicos que transitaba la corporación de The Beatles, Apple Corps.
dbo:abstract | 《You Never Give Me Your Money》是由英國搖滾樂團披頭四成員保羅·麥卡尼創作、收錄於專輯《艾比路》的1969年歌曲。（作品上是以藍儂-麥卡尼「Lennon–McCartney」的名義發表）
dbo:abstract | You Never Give me Your Money é uma canção dos Beatles composta por Paul McCartney, creditada a dupla Lennon-McCartney, e lançada no álbum Abbey Road de 1969. A gravação teve início no dia 6 de maio de 1969, e concluída em 21 de agosto de 1969. A canção dura 4 min e 2 s.
dbo:abstract | You Never Give Me Your Money est une chanson du groupe britannique les Beatles. Elle a été écrite par Paul McCartney, mais créditée Lennon/McCartney. Elle apparaît sur l’album Abbey Road sorti en 1969. Elle ouvre le fameux medley sur la face B du 33 tours original.
dbo:abstract | «You Never Give Me Your Money» (рус. Ты никогда не даёшь мне свои деньги) — песня группы «Битлз», открывающая кульминационное попурри на второй стороне альбома Abbey Road. Песня была написана Полом Маккартни (авторство приписано Леннону и Маккартни) и является своеобразной сатирой на финансовые пререкания внутри группы в начале 1969 года.
dbo:album | dbr:Abbey_Road
dbo:artist | dbr:The_Beatles
dbo:genre | dbr:Rock_music
dbo:producer | dbr:George_Martin
dbo:recordDate | 1969-05-06
dbo:recordDate | 0005-07-31
dbo:recordLabel | dbr:Apple_Records
dbo:recordedIn | dbr:Olympic_Sound_Studios
dbo:recordedIn | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Barnes,_London
dbo:releaseDate | 1969-09-26
dbo:runtime | 242.0
dbo:trackNumber | 9
dbo:wikiPageExternalLink | http://www.icce.rug.nl/~soundscapes/DATABASES/AWP/yngmym.shtml
dbo:wikiPageID | 2244659
dbo:wikiPageRevisionID | 745074265
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_published_by_Northern_Songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tape_loop
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Nine_Below_Zero
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Abbey_Road
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Nursery_rhyme
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sony/ATV_Music_Publishing
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Overdub
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Rock_music
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Crossfade_(audio_engineering)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Singing
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Honky-tonk
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Backing_vocalist
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Boogie-woogie
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/I_Want_You_(She's_So_Heavy)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:John_Lennon
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Abbey_Road_Studios
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1969_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Keith_West
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tape_loops
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Beatles_songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Wind_chime
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Jam_session
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Glenn_Tilbrook
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Northern_Songs
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Barnes,_London
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Harrison
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Fender_Telecaster
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Lennon–McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Lead_vocalist
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Drum_kit
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Piano
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Bass_guitar
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Let_It_Be_(album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Allen_Klein
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Here_Comes_the_Sun
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Apple_Records
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Continuum_International_Publishing_Group
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:George_Martin
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Tambourine
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Leslie_speaker
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Epiphone_Casino
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Happiness_Is_a_Warm_Gun
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Brian_Epstein
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Olympic_Sound_Studios
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mojo_(magazine)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:The_Beatles
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lennon–McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Ringo_Starr
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Paul_McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Beatles_(album)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sun_King_(song)
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Arpeggio
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Linda_McCartney
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_George_Martin
dbo:wikiPageWikiLink | dbr:Excerpt_from_A_Teenage_Opera
dbo:writer | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lennon–McCartney
dbp:wordnet_type | http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-song-noun-1
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1969_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_published_by_Northern_Songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Beatles_songs
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songs_written_by_Lennon–McCartney
dcterms:subject | http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Song_recordings_produced_by_George_Martin
http://purl.org/linguistics/gold/hypernym | dbr:Song
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatSongsPublishedByNorthernSongs
rdf:type | dbo:MusicalWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MusicalComposition107037465
rdf:type | http://schema.org/CreativeWork
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Wikicat1969Songs
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Recording104063661
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Music107020895
rdf:type | http://schema.org/MusicRecording
rdf:type | dbo:Single
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Song107048000
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatTheBeatlesSongs
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Signal106791372
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Communication100033020
rdf:type | http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/MusicalComposition_Song
rdf:type | dbo:Work
rdf:type | owl:Thing
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AuditoryCommunication107109019
rdf:type | dbo:Song
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WikicatSongRecordingsProducedByGeorgeMartin
rdf:type | http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Abstraction100002137
rdfs:comment | «You Never Give Me Your Money» (рус. Ты никогда не даёшь мне свои деньги) — песня группы «Битлз», открывающая кульминационное попурри на второй стороне альбома Abbey Road. Песня была написана Полом Маккартни (авторство приписано Леннону и Маккартни) и является своеобразной сатирой на финансовые пререкания внутри группы в начале 1969 года.
rdfs:comment | "You Never Give Me Your Money" is a song by the Beatles, appearing on their 1969 album Abbey Road. It was written by Paul McCartney (though credited to Lennon–McCartney) and documented the financial and personal difficulties facing the band. The track is the first track of the medley on side two of Abbey Road and was recorded in stages between May and August 1969.
rdfs:comment | You Never Give Me Your Money est une chanson du groupe britannique les Beatles. Elle a été écrite par Paul McCartney, mais créditée Lennon/McCartney. Elle apparaît sur l’album Abbey Road sorti en 1969. Elle ouvre le fameux medley sur la face B du 33 tours original.
rdfs:comment | ユー・ネヴァー・ギヴ・ミー・ユア・マネー(You Never Give Me Your Money)は、1969年に発表されたビートルズのアルバム『アビイ・ロード』に収録されたポール・マッカートニー作の曲でここから同アルバムのB面の特徴であるメドレーに入る。
rdfs:comment | You Never Give Me Your Money è un brano dei Beatles, scritto soprattutto da Paul McCartney ma accreditato, per convenzione, alla coppia Lennon-McCartney. Compare nell'LP Abbey Road, ed è posta all'inizio del long medley, che caratterizza la seconda facciata dell'album.
rdfs:comment | 《You Never Give Me Your Money》是由英國搖滾樂團披頭四成員保羅·麥卡尼創作、收錄於專輯《艾比路》的1969年歌曲。（作品上是以藍儂-麥卡尼「Lennon–McCartney」的名義發表）
rdfs:comment | „You Never Give Me Your Money” – utwór autorstwa Paula McCartneya, nagrany przez brytyjską grupę The Beatles. Piosenka znalazła się na albumie Abbey Road, wydanym w 1969 roku. Utwór rozpoczyna 16. minutowe zestawienie utworów nazwane „Abbey Road Medley”.
rdfs:comment | "You Never Give Me Your Money" es una canción de The Beatles que abre el medley culminante en el lado B del álbum Abbey Road. Fue escrita por Paul McCartney aunque atribuida como Lennon/McCartney. McCartney se inspiró al escribir esta canción en los problemas económicos que transitaba la corporación de The Beatles, Apple Corps.
rdfs:comment | You Never Give me Your Money é uma canção dos Beatles composta por Paul McCartney, creditada a dupla Lennon-McCartney, e lançada no álbum Abbey Road de 1969. A gravação teve início no dia 6 de maio de 1969, e concluída em 21 de agosto de 1969. A canção dura 4 min e 2 s.
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | You Never Give Me Your Money
rdfs:label | ユー・ネヴァー・ギヴ・ミー・ユア・マネー
owl:sameAs | http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ユー・ネヴァー・ギヴ・ミー・ユア・マネー
owl:sameAs | http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.06ytfd
owl:sameAs | http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
owl:sameAs | http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#wasDerivedFrom | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money?oldid=745074265
foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf | http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/You_Never_Give_Me_Your_Money
foaf:name | You Never Give Me Your Money

Specifikace FRBR entit v českém jazyce

Dílo
Dílo je abstraktní entita; neexistuje žádný materiální objekt, který by bylo možné označit jako dílo. Dílo rozeznáváme pomocí jednotlivých realizací nebo vyjádření díla, ale dílo samo existuje pouze ve shodě obsahu mezi různými vyjádřeními díla. Když mluvíme o Homérově Iliadě jako o díle, není bodem naší pozornosti určitý přednes nebo text díla, ale intelektuální výtvor, který se nachází za všemi různými vyjádřeními díla.
Různé texty zahrnující revize a aktualizace předchozího textu jsou jednoduše považovány za vyjádření téhož díla (tj. různé texty nejsou považovány za samostatná díla). Podobně se zkrácení nebo rozšíření stávajícího textu nebo doplnění částí nebo doprovodu k hudební skladbě považují za různá vyjádření téhož díla. Překlady z jednoho jazyka do druhého, hudební přepisy a úpravy a verze dabovaných filmů nebo filmů opatřených titulky jsou rovněž považovány za odlišná vyjádření téhož původního díla.
Vyjádření
Druhou entitou definovanou v modelu je vyjádření: určitá intelektuální nebo umělecká realizace díla ve formě abecedně-číselného, hudebního nebo choreografického zápisu, zvukového záznamu, obrazového statického nebo pohyblivého záznamu, objektu atd., nebo kombinace těchto forem.
Vyjádření je určitá intelektuální nebo umělecká forma, kterou dílo nabývá vždy, když je "realizováno". Vyjádření zahrnuje například určitá slova, věty, odstavce atd., které jsou výsledkem realizace díla ve formě textu, nebo určité noty, frázování atd., které jsou výsledkem realizace hudebního díla. Hranice entity vyjádření jsou však definovány tak, aby se vyloučily aspekty fyzické formy, jako např. druh písma a formát stránky, jež nejsou součástí intelektuální nebo umělecké realizace samotného díla.
Jakákoliv revize či modifikace textu se považuje za nové vyjádření, bez ohledu na to, jak velká modifikace byla provedena.
Provedení
Entita definovaná jako provedení zahrnuje široký okruh dokumentů, jako jsou rukopisy, knihy, periodika, mapy, plakáty, zvukové záznamy, filmy, videozáznamy, disky CDROM, smíšené dokumenty atd. Provedení jako entita představuje všechny hmotné objekty, které mají stejné vlastnosti pokud jde o intelektuální obsah a fyzickou formu.
Když se realizuje dílo, může být výsledné vyjádření díla fyzicky ztělesněno na nosiči, jako jsou např. papír, zvuková kazeta, videokazeta, plátno, sádra aj. Tato fyzická forma tvoří provedení díla. V některých případech se může vyrobit pouze jeden fyzický exemplář tohoto provedení díla (např. autorův rukopis, zvukový záznam na pásce pro zvukový historický archiv, originální olejomalba atd.). V jiných případech se vyrobí více kopií pro účely veřejného šíření nebo distribuce.
Jednotka
Entita definovaná jako jednotka je konkrétní entita. V mnoha případech se jedná o jeden materiální objekt (např. výtisk jednosvazkové monografie, jedna zvuková kazeta atd.). Existují však případy, kdy entita definovaná jako jednotka obsahuje více než jeden materiální objekt (např. monografie vydaná jako dva samostatné svazky, záznam vydaný na třech samostatných kompaktních deskách atd.).
V pojmech intelektuálního obsahu a fyzické formy je běžně jednotka jako exemplář provedení totéž jako samotné provedení. Mohou se však vyskytnout rozdíly mezi jednotlivými jednotkami, přestože jednotky náležejí ke stejnému provedení; tyto odlišnosti jsou výsledkem činností prováděných mimo působnost výrobce provedení (např. poškození vzniklé po vyrobení jednotky nebo vazba provedená knihovnou aj.)

Specification of FRBR entities

Work
Instances categorized as belonging to the FRBR class Work are concepts identified in artistic and intellectual expressions. The substance of a work is an idea.
A collection of works (e.g. a periodical) is a work as well as its members.
A work is a product of an intellectual process of which we have only indirect evidence (e.g. its expression, work order, etc.).
Expression
Instances categorized as belonging to the FRBR class Expression are intellectual or artistic realisations of works in the form of identifiable immaterial objects. Expressions cannot exist without a physical carrier, but do not depend on any single carrier. They can exist on any number of carriers simultaneously.
Potential carriers of an expression also include human memory.
Any change in form might create a new expression (e.g. alpha-numeric notation to spoken word) and it might require knowing the genre to identify features which are essential to the expression (e.g. typeface and page layout).
A collection of expressions (e.g. an anthology of poems) is a an expression as well as the members of the collection themselves.
Manifestation
Instances categorized as belonging to the FRBR class Manifestation represent all items that have been created as part of a series (e.g. an edition of a book). The item must be identifiable as a copy belonging to a manifestation, but does not need to exhibit all the features or traits of the manifestation (e.g. due to production events).
Physical objects (e.g. a manuscript or draft) not intended to be produced in multiple copies are still considered to be manifestations.
Item
Instances categorized as belonging to the FRBR class Item are physical copies - exemplars of a single manifestation.